Hello Hello
Everyone Welcome to the Principal of our YouTube channel
In today's video we
will discuss why ICICI Lombard's share
fell by more than four percent
Some important news came in this company, so we will
know whether the share fall was due to that news
or there was some other reason and what should be our strategy going forward Let's move ahead, so first of all
we will start with the company's lawyer Isi
Lombard is in the non-life
insurance business, that is,
except life insurance, it does all other insurance
products like car
insurance, health insurance,
travel insurance, two wheeler
insurance, home insurance and weather
insurance and if their market
capitalization is seen then it is around 74 thousand crores
which makes it a large cap company
Talking about share holding,
51.81 percent share is with the promoter which is
ICICI Bank Apart from this, 29.75% is with
foreign institutions, around 12% is with
romantic institutions and
around 7% is with retail
shareholders and nothing special has been seen in its share holding  If we
talk about the recent functions, you must have
seen that both its sales and profit
increased in this quarter and the
main reason for this was Kuwait. Because of Kuwait, there were a
lot of claims in the health insurance business segment and they had to bear it very easily
and if you must be thinking
that last year too the insurance was valid but
then there was not so much loss then the
reason for this is that last year it was such due to which the
economic impact was more, there was a lot of loss and the
hospitalization of people was
not that much, the maximum amount had gone up to 1 lakh
and this time it had gone up to more than 4 lakhs, so
because of that a
lot of people made claims in health insurance due to which
they had to bear a loss of 508 crores
whereas if compared to last year then
they had a huge profit of 38-38 crores
and as told, this is mainly due to health
insurance claims and
because of this second wave and if it is
seen in the same way as if they collect a premium of ₹100
In health insurance, if their profit
came back to 153, then Avery
Insurance had to bear a loss of around ₹1. So
let's move ahead.
Now we will talk about the latest news, what
happened due to which the
stock has fallen so much. There were two news in it, out of which the
first news seems positive.
That news is that IRDA (
Insurance Regulatory and Development
Authority of India) has granted its final
approval for the demerger of Bharti AXA's
general insurance business. Due to
this, now that business will be
transferred to ICICI Lombard
by way of this scheme of arrangement. Its
Mohan has already received regulatory approval
and has also received approval from the shareholders and Twitter. Its
point date will be April 120.
Please, it will be considered that the final
approval has come, so the transfer will be
effective in three days from the date of final
approval. So this will happen within three days.
Actually, it will be considered that it has become
effective. Apart from this, ITI has
also told ICICI Bank that since
you are the promoter, you should infuse capital into it.
If there is any business growth or any
solvency requirement
due to this merger, then you should infuse extra capital for that.
And the ultimate scheme
in this will be that the shareholders of Bharti AXA will
get two shares of ICICI Lombard in exchange of 115 shares.
And whenever the MS Word
merger is completed, Bharti AXA,
their promoter Bharti
Enterprises, and Ek Saya will
merge with their general insurance business
and after that only one company will remain,
ICICI Lombard. So this news
overall because they were
waiting for its approval for a long time, so I think this should
be positive. And the second news has come
that IRDA has sent its letter for its final
approval of Bharti AXA merger.
Apart from this, they have also approved in that letter
that  ICICI Bank
because it is the promoter of ICICI
Lombard, it can reduce its stake by
230% and right now its stake which
we saw in the last match is more than 51%, it is
around 52%. The
reduction of this stake will be
subject to compliance and provision of
Insurance Act and I think
that perhaps the market has not taken this news well
because if they sell the
shares, the promoter's share will reduce which is
considered negative and last year also when
such a bank sold its stake a
little less than 4%, then
Lombard's share is the most
questioned night, so it is
possible that this news is being taken a little negatively,
so let's move ahead,
now we will discuss that this is an
opportunity that this 4%
correction has been seen or this stock should also be
appointed and brought down because the
promoters are leaving, so first if we
look at its performance, it has fallen by 4%
Even after this, it
fell by 11.38 percent in this week, that is, three to three and a half
percent, Khargone had already shown this
and after that, the performance of one month, this is the
performance after falling by four percent,
so there is an increase of eight percent, there is
also eight percent increase in three months, this year of Anna
and this is 2.7 percent big, so that means
around three percent, in which four percent
fall is 100, so seven percent can be
lost and 21 percent in 1 year and
8 percent in 3 years and if
we talk about the analysts, then the
analysts in that are giving it a 60% buy rating and
according to them the average price should be 1672,
which probably had
reached very close to it just a day or two ago
and they believe that on the upper side it can
go up to 1937 and on the lower side even to 11 centuries or even
to Rasulallah and if we look at the average price then
1672, which is about 7 percent higher than today's rate.
If you want to know my opinion
on this,
I will share a few things
with you. Firstly, the
transfer of Bharti AXA should be a positive,
so the bank will be able to penetrate further into the general insurance business.
This will have an energy impact, so
I think it should be positive.
Secondly, if we look at the reasons, this
year the stock has fallen by four percent to almost
three percent, which is
growing rapidly in the market, so it is not special, so
now we have not shown any special interest in it.
We saw that the reasons for this were also that
their health insurance business suffered a
lot of losses and it seems that now
as it is gradually getting under control, the
world seems to be over for the company.
Apart from that, if we talk about their business model,
India is definitely under
pressure and with the arrival of Co-Water, people have become
more aware about insurance and
I think health insurance is
growing a lot and in general the demand for insurance will also
increase. So it is a big player in that, so it
definitely  If it will be beneficial then my opinion is that if we
look at it now, it has
grown by around eight percent in the last one month including
today's fall, so
I think that maybe we can wait a little bit,
but these tips here, brothers,
definitely in my opinion, the
overall perspective looks quite good and if there is a
proper correction in it, then it can be taken for the
long term, for the future,
as I put it in the display every time, this is
my personal opinion, if
you want to invest in it, then you should
talk to your financial advisor or do your research before
investing,
thank you so much for watching
my video and now you can comment that
if you do it or there is any other reason which is
unknown and we will find out in some time, then
please like and comment and thanks a lot
for watching the video, bless you all.